Episode 95
2 months after
the Conquest of İnegöl
Just like the old days, my love.
The one who loves the most,
runs the fastest.
Karayel!
Do you hear it? Huh?
What do they say to us?
But they don't know that...
we become the wind and howl
everywhere for love!
Show it then, Osman Bey.
Alaca is still strong.
She can go through the wind.
Keep that in mind.
Karayel suffered a lot for us.
But now we have İltutan.
İltutan is fast too.
His renown makes a home out
of the lands he runs through.
Once he eats Alaca's dusts...
I hope it won't lose his speed.
That's what you say?
Then, Cerkutay!
Oh, Cerkutay.
I should give these weapons
to you.
You know, they'll make
me heavier.
I need to be faster.
For speed, you give up on your
weapons, Osman.
It's that important, huh?
It's important.
Then, we should let
our horses speak.
We won't stop until that greens.
Alaca, don't let me down.
İltutan.
Come on, son.
Come on, then!
Let's become wind for love!
Come on!
İltutan!
No one knows the mind of your
owner better than you!
Come on, don't disappoint me.
Alaca! If you get behind,
your white hair will get dust!
Speed up!
Let's not pollute our love.
Bala.
You are a good rider.
Thank you, my bey.
Come on.
So, we are even again, Osman?
Just like our love, Bala.
Mashallah to İltutan.
He's been carrying you
for a time now.
Let's sit here.
We have many supporters.
Our brothers, alps, horses.
But...
there is none like the strength of
the house.
My heart is filled with the love
of my children and jihad.
But you are always behind me.
May Allah protect you.
I face all these hardships because
of your love.
I get my strength from you.
May Allah protect you
and our children.
Amin.
May Allah keep us together.
Take off your hand!
We need horses!
And some gold!
It appears that you have both.
Is that so?
Come, then.
Come.
Come and get beaten.
You are brave.
Brave people don't live long.
Do as we say...
and we might spare your life.
It's been a while since we mounted
to face the winds, my bey.
And it's been a while since we've
beaten their kind.
Don't hold me back.
As you wish.
Come on, then!
Bala!
Are you alright?
I am, Osman.
Come on! Come on!
My bey!
My bey.
Are you alright?
My bey, your horses don't run.
They fly!
We couldn't come in time!
Dogs!
They made a mistake.
They didn't know who you are.
Don't worry.
They can't bite us.
Return to the tribe.
Then, you'll find out where
did they come from.
Yes, my bey.
Stay safe, my bey.
You too.
Thank you.
-My bey.
-Come on.
Come on.
Caravansarai on the road
Sit.
Don't stand.
Our table is always open to guests.
The only thing I want to
see on your table...
is Osman's head.
Don't hurry.
Everything has a time.
Can someone reach victory
without patience?
Don't speak like your idiot master
Darius!
He loved waiting.
Nikola too.
They are all in their graves now.
I waited but did not face
the enemy...
but I stood beside him.
I stood behind him.
I gained his trust.
Why is Kayı's banner bigger
than the others?
It wasn't like this before.
The answer to the question is
in the question, my bey.
It wasn't like this.
As Kayı grows,
so does its banner.
Until it expands to the
whole world.
But don't forget...
with its might,
so grows its problems.
Thank you.
Come.
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam.
Come, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
We heard that Turkmens are flowing to
the West after the conquest.
Because they see İnegöl and Bilecik
as home.
They love you.
Thank you.
That's we do conquest.
There won't be a single Turkmen
without home.
We'll give villages and tribes
to everyone.
It seems that this won't be enough.
If they are flowing here...
then, we'll march together.
We'll flood into the walls of Bursa.
İznik, Yenişehir.
We'll march altogether.
As long as...
we stand together.
The future of the Turks is on
your hands, Osman Bey.
The reach of the Islam flag...
is in your scope.
Now tell me.
What's your target?
Bursa.
My scope and cause is longer
than my life.
Osman will target Yenişehir after
İnegöl and Bilecik.
If he can take that, you'll be his
right hand for life.
Your dagger won't hurt him.
Do you know my dagger, Romanos?
Or, do you know how far
I can go?
I spent my years behind
Osman that I hate!
I stayed loyal to him.
I've beaten my grudge.
Now tell me.
Who am I?
Barkın. Bey.
Are you afraid of me?
Good. So will Osman.
Back then Osman asked for the villages
around Yenişehir from the emperor.
Now he'll target Yenişehir.
Osman's targets are bigger
than years, Romanos.
What will we do?
Will we stand idle?
You are a commander. You'll
take cautions.
He'll take Yenişehir and make it
his quarters.
Stack soldiers.
Then, he'll target Yondhisar Castle.
Will that be enough to
stop Osman?
Osman is strengthened by
the wind of conquest.
It's difficult to beat him on
the battlefield.
But we'll destroy him.
The war will be over before
it starts.
Come on. Eat our meal.
Get some strength.
Don't fade when you hear
Osman's real target is Bursa.
Bursa is far from you.
Bursa is difficult for you, Osman Bey.
Maybe you shouldn't set seeds
early?
The one with strong roots
can green in the hardest winter.
Surely, it will take years.
But I know one thing.
A mare that gives birth in İnegöl,
will cool down in Bursa's waters.
There is no sooner or later.
There are hard paths and
harder people who walk them.
Your move is ready for the field.
But inside?
If you can't control the flood of Turkmens,
decay from inside will begin.
We host the incoming Turkmens
in Bilecik and İnegöl.
We gave them home but
now it won't be enough.
For that reason, I'll take
another land.
Before Bursa, Yenişehir.
We'll take Yenişehir.
And for Bursa's siege,
we'll make it our quarters.
The flooding Turkmens will
make it home.
We say that your trouble grows
with you.
The bigger trouble is in where
you are heading.
Victories of Bilecik and İnegöl
is boiling Constantinople.
An army is being prepared.
And the Mongols are mobilizing
again.
Turkmens, caravans, villages
are getting raided.
We are ready for all kinds
of troubles.
We sent alps everywhere against
the leaderless Mongols.
They will be killed at sight.
But the army...
we'll take Yenişehir before the
army comes.
If we take Yenişehir, they can face us
with as many soldiers as they want.
The road to Bursa will be open.
May Allah put you in easy circumstances.
May Allah bless your jihad.
Thank you.
Allah's cause is in our heart.
It shows us the way. It makes the
circumstances easier.
May Allah bless your jihad.
Thank you.
Bursa?
-What are you saying?
-Bursa, yes.
If we don't stop Osman, he'll take
Yenişehir and Bursa.
This will ruin your plans too.
Fortunately, the emperor
is preparing a great army.
He should. He should.
I'll send a part of this army to
Yenişehir and Yondhisar.
If it's true, we must form
a good defensive line.
You can't stop Osman by
defending.
We'll attack.
If Osman grew...
we'll take away little tiny parts
from him.
Mind always shows the
same path.
I'm happy so agree with you.
My plan is ready.
My pawn is ready.
Tell me.
There are some leaderless Mongols
who joined the rebellion in Süremiş.
They are out of order.
They need gold to survive.
I'll send them to Osman.
Just as you said. Piece by piece.
You thought well.
But Çobanoğlu Tribe's bey and son...
are going to visit Kayı Tribe.
They respect Ertuğrul Bey
and Osman.
You are giving bad news today.
Let me give you good news then.
Ali's son Mustafa isn't acting
by his own mind.
He acts as his Lala Ahmed says.
What do you think?
Ahmed and I are students of Master
Darius that you don't like.
Ahmed is my friend.
If Ahmed is on our side,
so is Mustafa.
What will we do? Provoke him?
Mustafa isn't the bey yet.
But...
we'll provoke Mustafa so much that
he'll provoke his father Ali.
When Ali Bey differs from Osman...
the beys will be loyal
to Ali Bey.
Then, the war will end before it
starts for Osman.
When the great Roman army
marches...
Osman won't have power left
to fight.
When Osman vanishes...
only one person will stand in
these lands.
İnegöl Castle
-Are they fresh?
-Yes, fresh.
Show me your skills.
Osman Bey is coming!
Welcome, Osman Bey!
Salam Alaikum!
May God protect you, Osman Bey!
Welcome, Osman Bey!
Thank you.
May God make you stronger!
We prospered because of you!
How is the building of the church going,
Priest Hristo?
Our people are working. They don't hold
back their goods or efforts.
Your alps are helping too.
Thank you.
Let's finish it soon. The people's needs
should be provided.
Osman Bey's tent and Turgut Bey's
audience is always open to the people.
May God keep you with us.
Thank you.
-Welcome, Osman Bey.
-Thank you, Turgut Bey.
-How is the tribe?
-We have a big guest.
Çobanoğlu Ali Bey is coming.
The tribe is getting ready.
Ali Bey! He is welcome.
-Come, Osman Bey.
-Thank you.
Thank you.
My sisters!
Let's put in the extra effort!
Çobanoğlu Ali Bey is coming!
And he is coming to congratulate
Osman Bey!
Let's host them to make
Osman Bey proud.
We will! We will! Our women are
capable in fighting and cooking.
Alaca, be careful with the tents
of our guests.
We prepared everything with Zehra.
Everything is done.
Çobanoğlu Ali Bey is coming
to congratulate Osman Bey!
Thank you.
If we get Çobanoğlu Tribe's
support, there will be more conquests.
With Allah's approval,
that support is ready, Malhun Hatun.
Since Ali Bey heard the victory of İnegöl,
he has been talking about Osman Bey.
Thank Allah.
My angelic girl.
Well done.
Bala. Wait.
Let's do it together.
Thank you, Aygül.
I should check.
Ayşe.
It's been a long time since
you last talked.
Is it not the time yet?
Bala!
Mother Bala!
Women, bring water!
Bala!
She is breathing.
Women!
Come on!
Brother! Brother Orhun!
Wait, brother.
What happened?
I was with you a moment ago.
Missed me already?
An evangel, brother.
It's for you.
From Holafira.
But I want to use your dagger that
you don't let me touch.
Sure, brother.
Sure.
Brother.
My dear brother.
Take it.
What does it say?
Is she alright?
Did she arrive safely?
She is alright.
Her aunt is taking good
care of her.
Everything is as she wants.
She already missed our tribe a lot.
She says that she'll come back
one day.
Inshallah, brother.
Inshallah.
If İnegöl is a lake...
Bursa is a sea.
It won't be easy to take it.
Sieging Bursa and İznik...
might take years.
Firstly...
we'll get the caravan routes.
We'll cut their veins.
We'll spot the sources of
the city and take them over.
Their mines, farms and everthing.
This will be our move against them.
The emperor is building an
army against us.
His intention is to take us out of
these lands.
-Let them come, my bey.
-No.
The real bravery is needed soon.
We have only one arrow to shoot.
Yenişehir.
We'll position there.
And we'll defend it.
If we can't stop the incoming
army...
İnegöl that we took with the lives
of many martyrs and my brother...
will be taken away.
If we start retreating...
then...
we might have to retreat to
the Kayı Tribe.
So, there is no place
for mistakes.
Precautions or war.
We'll do anything, Osman Bey.
But what will we do to the leaderless
Mongols?
They are troubling the
caravans and the villagers.
So, the trouble continues in the
east and in the west.
Cerkutay and Konur are tracing them.
They'll take care of them.
Thank you, my bey.
-Master Davud.
-My bey.
You'll go to Yenişehir with
Kumral Abdal.
Get capable masters with you.
Dervishes with smooth tongues.
Firstly...
firstly, you'll conquer
the hearts.
Priest Hristo will come with you.
As you order, my bey.
We can conquer any heart
with the light of our Allah.
We'll go and take them.
Thank Allah.
Our target is the order of the world.
But the Kayı can't do it
alone.
Çobanoğlu Ali Bey will visit us.
He is a great bey.
And it requires a great
preparation.
He'll be hosted as he deserves it.
You see it fit.
Come on, then. Everyone to
their jobs.
May our jihad be blessed.
Thank you.
Thank you, mother.
All those years...
I've waited to reunite with you.
I lost my father as soon
as I reunited with him!
Do you want me to not reunite
with you either, mother?
Always...
I dreamed of sitting around a table
altogether.
Now I'm with you.
I'm in my tribe, my home now!
But now you keep your voice
away from me!
What is this for, mother?
Didn't you...
tell me that I'm a martyr's son
and I should stand tall?
Look at me!
I stand tall and proud of
my father.
What about you, mother?
Why are you silent?
You don't drop a single tear.
What about your heart?
Is it only your bey
who is a martyr?
My father died!
Father!
When my only medicine is
your voice...
you kept it away from me.
I'll make you speak, mother!
You will speak, mother!
Come on!
Come on, you too!
Is this how you face the enemy?
Come on!
Won't you talk, mother?
When will you talk?
When my burial comes to the tribe?
Alps! Come on! To Osman Bey!
Look...
I am telling you, Romanos...
...we were both trained by Master Arius.
That dagger on my throat is ours.
Barkın, my dear friend!
You get old but...
...you never lose your skills.
I didn't even hear a crackle.
This is how people are.
They forget their names but don't forget
their training.
If you have raised Mustafa, son of
Çobanoğlu Ali Bey like this...
...it means he is as dangerous as you.
Mustafa.
Anger runs in his veins, not blood.
It is very easy to dominate such a person
and to raise him as you wish.
Tell me, Ahmet.
Tell me more.
His father Ata Bey's calmness drives him
crazy.
His blood boils.
He is also the angriest at the fact that
he left those conquests to Kayı.
So, he is perfect for our game?
He would drown Osman in a spoon of water
if he could.
He is a very furious young man.
I will force this side of him.
If I can provoke Mustafa...
...he might convince his father.
Good.
Osman will turn into ash...
...between a strong Turk Tribe and
the strong army of Rome.
And the cleverest, the fiercest man...
...will start this fire.
Indeed, it has already begun.
What is going on here?
No.
Don't be afraid.
Come here.
What happened here?
Who did this?
The evil Mongols stopped us on our way.
They raided our goods.
Come here. Come here.
Why did they let you live?
These devil Mongols never let anyone live
after their raids.
Your alps, Osman Bey.
They came just in time.
We would already be dead if it weren't
for them.
The Mongols ran this way when they saw
them.
Your alps went after them.
Let's go after them.
As you order, my Bey.
Let's go, my Bey.
Let them know what they get for hurting
the innocent.
Of course.
What happened, Cerkutay?
I found some Mongol tracks.
I knew something was wrong.
The tracks led us to here, my Bey.
Were they crowded?
Ten or fifteen, my Bey.
They took the goods and ran away.
We killed all of them and didn't leave...
...a single good of these merchants
to them.
Share these goods among the people.
Indemnify the damages.
Take the wounded to the healing tent.
As you order, my Bey.
Thank you, Osman Bey. May God protect
you.
Don't worry.
No one under my rule will be mistreated.
Whoever harms my people, punishing
him...
...is my holy duty.
Even if people's noses bleed, I will ask
for their account now.
Don't worry.
We are grateful, Osman Bey.
So, these dogs have settled around.
Konur, you will join Turgut Bey with
Aktemur.
As you order, my Bey.
Cerkutay.
Yes, my Bey?
Go after these Mongols.
As you order, my Bey.
I will destroy their dens.
Her face looks very pale.
She has been working since morning prayer.
I told her not to but she didn't listen.
She fell to the ground just like that.
I was so worried.
Ah, Bala, Ah.
She will be fine, right, Healer Sister?
She got weakened, but she will regain her
strength by drinking this.
-I hope so.
Mother!
Is my mother fine? Did she get ill?
She is fine and she will be better, son.
She caught a little cold.
Let's leave and let her rest.
Zehra.
You stay with her.
Call me if anything happens.
Don't worry.
What does Healer Hatun say?
I should stay with her.
She may need something.
Healer Hatun says that your mother is a
little tired, my Alaaddin.
But she is fine.
Don't worry, my Alaaddin.
Healer Sister is...
...with her. Don't be afraid.
Let's go...
...and let Bala sleep.
Come on.
Roadside Caravanserai
In the name of Allah.
Osman Bey welcomes us on the way.
Are the roads not safe, Turgut Bey?
The roads are never safe in this area.
But only if we are not there.
We clear the roads from any looters.
Thank you. Thank you.
Your visit also honored us, Ali Bey.
Welcoming a Mighty Turk Bey like you
is an honor for us.
Don't worry.
Your caravan on the way will be
accompanied to Söğüt.
It is under our protection.
The real honor is to sit at this table
with you, Turgut Bey.
All right.
The real honor is...
...war!
Come on, continue to tell from where you
left off.
You entered İnegöl with the ram head
while pouring boiling oil from your head.
What happened after that?
Later...
...our skilled valiants...
...Osman Bey...
...and brother Gündüz, who was a martyr,
risking his life to take İnegöl.
And many other alps.
Thanks to them.
Yes, we took over the castle...
... but we took every step with our blood
and soul.
I've heard about both Gündüz Bey and
his heroism, Aktemur.
Your father became a son befitting
his ancestors.
May he rest in peace.
Thank you, Ali Bey.
I actually wonder about the Emperor's face
when he took Nikola's head.
Aren't you afraid of the Emperor's wrath?
Is this a smart move?
Osman Bey and those who support him
do not have fear in their hearts.
But they scare others.
We sent Nikola's head to our opponents...
... as an example.
There is no conquest with fear.
Praise be to you!
Fear is for cowards.
The Turks don't fear.
I understood where Osman Bey's power
came from.
From the valiant men who lined up behind
him and believed in him and his cause.
One who leans his back on the mountains...
...makes his range endless.
Thank you.
Osman Bey's power comes from his cause.
And those who have the same cause
support him.
Thank you, Ali Bey.
Thank you.
Father?
-Welcome, my Bey.
-Welcome, Osman Bey.
Welcome, my Bey.
Father!
Fatma!
My little sheep.
Come here.
Sons.
Alaaddin.
Are you upset with each other?
Bala mother is ill, father.
Alaaddin.
Tell me, what happened to your mother?
My mother is in the tent, father.
She doesn't look good.
She passed out in the kitchen.
My mother is with her.
Is that so?
Let me see her. Wait here.
Don't be afraid, brother.
Nothing will happen to our mother.
I hope so, brother.
I hope so.
Malhun...
...how is Bala?
She doesn't feel good, Osman. The healer
is with her.
She will be fine soon.
She worked so much.
She also tired herself in the kitchen
today for the guests.
That must be the reason.
I informed our Sheik.
He will be here in the evening.
He will surely heal Bala with his prayer.
I hope so. I hope so.
Let me see her.
She just fell asleep, my Bey.
But if you please...
...you can see her.
No, let her sleep.
I won't wake her up.
She must rest.
Inform me if anything happens.
Sons.
Father, how is my mother?
Don't worry.
Your mother is fine and she will be
better.
I told you. Bala mother is strong.
Nothing will happen to her.
She is the leader of the women
warriors.
I hope so, brother.
Yes, she is.
She is strong.
But she can't even open her eyes.
I am afraid that something will happen
to her.
No way.
We are all human.
Mothers get tired sometimes as well.
Mothers get ill sometimes as well.
But you will see. She will wake up as if
nothing happened.
And she will stand behind us like
a mountain.
She will rise from the ashes like a
phoenix.
As long as mothers have children who
pray for them like you...
...nothing will happen to them.
The mothers take their strength from their
children.
Come here.
Father, we took Bilecik and İnegöl.
Yes, we did.
Thankfully.
Thankfully. But what about Bursa?
When will we take Bursa?
When will we go there?
Taking Bursa isn't that easy, my Orhan.
Where did this come from?
He keeps talking about it.
My brother dreams of standing on the walls
of Bursa.
Praise be!
If we take Bursa, the infidels will have
no power in the east.
They will be weakened.
This will open the way for many other
conquests, father.
When we take Bursa, our trade will
prosper.
Caravans will never stop.
Because the Constantinople's trade will
be depending on us.
Praise be to my valiants!
Good for you.
From now on...
...our target is Bursa.
Come on.
I wasn't there in İnegöl but I want to
fight beside you in Bursa, father.
I hope so, son.
I hope those days are soon.
Roadside Caravanserai
Despite all the mess in the far away...
...you did a great job, Turgut Bey.
You have won victories beyond your
strength and numbers.
Isn't that the real skill?
Even though you are few, you make more
with your heart.
But I don't understand you Konuralp.
You were the commander of Mighty Seljuk
and now you are the alp to a Bey.
Brag about conquering a castle while you
used to rule cities.
This must be going down in the world.
Hear yourself, Mustafa Bey.
We are supporting Osman Bey for the cause
of Allah--
They say it's better to be a head to
a calf than a foot to an ox.
You are doing that, right?
In the state, your opponent was abundant
and your position was weak.
Now you are a rich man beside Osman Bey.
They have no money, my Bey.
They keep spending what they stole
or plundered from the Sultan.
Aktemur!
Hear yourself!
If not, you don't need to hear at all!
We wanted to host you since you were
our guests.
But you are not our guest anymore due to
your senseless talks.
Get hold of your alps!
We won't listen to those who slander the
people that died for the Turk nation!
If you don't punish him, we know how to
do.
There is no need, right?
I will kill all of you! Devils!
Those who are angry with two sentences
are trying to establish a state.
What do you expect from people living
in tents...
... after winning so many victories
and castles?
Don't cross the line!
It won't be our fault if you keep talking!
Come on, talk!
What is going on here?
Ahmet!
Mustafa, Turgut Bey, stop!
They wounded my alp!
Father, is this going to
remain unpenalized?
Your Alp exceeded his limits, Ali Bey.
He tried to attack once he was forgiven.
Ali Bey!
We kept silent until now because
but now...
What is your duty, Ahmet?
Serving as a model for Mustafa.
Is your duty to make a scene in where
we are guests?
My Bey.
No need for explanation.
Things are obvious.
Neither Turgut Bey nor Konur Alp
holds their sword.
But your swords are ready to swing!
Sorry for the inconvenience, Ali Bey.
We wouldn't want to host you like that.
Well done, Turgut Bey.
Whoever talks against the ones
whose intentions are clear...
...shall confront me.
So as to support Osman Bey
I came to this land!
He is the only hope of Turks!
If I see such vulgarity again...
even if it's my son or friend,
I won't be merciful!
Bala.
If wind touches your hair,
my heart gets cold.
Open your eyes.
Osman weakens when he
sees you like this.
Give me strength, Bala.
Bala. Open your eyes.
Bala!
Osman!
Are you alright?
Come, come, come.
What happened to you?
The healer says it's fine.
I'm alright.
Are you tiring yourself too much?
I heard it from Aygül.
You got bad at the soup kitchen.
Bala.
You are smiling.
What is this?
-Osman.
-Yes?
I was suspicious but...
I got sure after seeing
the healer...
What is it?
You'll have another child, Osman.
A baby!
What are you saying?
Really?
Mashallah!
Mashallah! Mashallah!
Thank Allah!
Thank Allah, Bala!
Bala!
Thank Allah!
My love!
My phoenix!
Our family is growing,
expanding!
Thank Allah!
How is my mother?
I can't eat anything.
Be at ease, my shehzad.
There is good in what
seems to be bad.
Your mother will be fine.
Just pray.
I always pray.
I always pray for mother
from inside.
Mashallah to you.
Father. Isn't my mother coming?
Sit, Alahaddin.
Sit.
Your mother is fine.
She'll be better, inshallah.
Inshallah.
My sheik. my children.
An evangel!
You'll have another sibling.
Our family is growing.
We are growing in numbers.
Thank Allah!
Mashallah. Mashallah.
Thank Allah.
-Thank Allah.
May Allah keep the parents
around the baby, Osman Bey.
Amin, my sheik.
Amin. Inshallah.
May it come with fortune, Osman Bey.
Amin, my Malhun.
Congratulations, Osman Bey.
May Allah bless it.
Thank you.
We'll have another sibling, huh?
If you allow it, I want
to see my mother.
Alahaddin. Wait, son.
Eat first.
You'll see your mother
after she rests.
Come on now.
Enjoy it.
With the name of Allah.
Fatma was crying about beying
the youngest.
Now you won't be the youngest.
My prayers are answered,
my sheik grandfather.
I'll be an older sister!
Mashallah to you.
You couldn't stay the smallest
forever!
-May I enter, my bey?
-Come in!
My bey, Kosses is here. He wants to
talk to you about something important.
Why are you keeping him outside?
Take him in.
Come on now.
With the name of Allah.
My tiger.
Oh, my Gündüz Bey.
As he was a brave bey...
he was also a merciful father.
He was destined to see his son Aktimur
and the conquest of İnegöl.
Salam Alaikum, brothers.
-Alaikum Salam.
With the name of Allah.
He was an older brother
to me.
From now, Aktimur is mine
to protect.
He will be at ease, right?
Sure, he made it home for us
as he gave his life there.
And he was buried there.
Gündüz Bey. May he rest in peace.
Amin.
Lord Kosses sent you regards.
Since his castle was taken,
Kosses isn't a lord, brother.
He is a valiant sharpening his sword
for battle, just like us.
You are right, Boran.
You are right.
True. He is more valiant than
many valiants.
He is an alp who'll go
to battles.
Lord Kosses isn't a Muslim.
How can he be an all?
Maybe he isn't now.
But who can know tomorrow, Şamil?
One day you look and see
him burning with the flames of Islam.
Maybe more Muslim than any of us?
Thank you, Brother Boran.
Inshallah.
Inshallah, brother.
What will we say to Osman Bey?
We won't hold the father responsible
for a child's disrespect.
Ali Bey gave the answer.
It's not our business now.
What are they after?
They are both ill-intentioned.
May Allah give him a long life but
when Ali Bey passes away...
if he gets the throne,
there will be troubles.
It's easier to feel sorrow
for one of your own, Konur.
But feeling good about his victory
takes courage.
It's unfortunate that those who are of
our own blood isn't feeling good.
We know Mustafa Bey's wound.
He is offended.
It's atabey Ahmed who is scratching
his wound.
He gives him all the ideas.
Whatever.
Our duty is to be careful.
Further speaking of this will
be gossiping. It's not us.
Aktimur. The roads are full
of marauders.
We'll take the caravan to Söğüt
with Konur.
Mustafa and Ahmed will be with us.
You'll accompany Ali Bey.
Osman Bey always says that a great
should be greeted by a great.
And as my martyr brother
Gündüz's son...
you are great to me.
I have no other wish but to be
worth to my father and uncle.
With my life, Turgut Bey.
Thank you.
Insolent!
They don't know their words
or moves!
But I know what to do.
Know how to control your
wrath first, Mustafa.
This is the bey's way.
The bey's way is attacking.
Is it the bey's way to insult your son
against the others?
Mustafa, you know how your father
respects Ertuğrul Ghazi.
He grew up with his stories.
That's why he trusts Osman Bey.
He trusts Osman because he
trusts Ertuğrul.
But he doesn't trust his own son.
Why? Because he doesn't even trust
himself.
He thinks it's greatness to stay
back in the shadows.
Osman should do the conquests,
he should gain renown!
If he says he is the state,
who will stand against him?
You will, Mustafa.
Before it comes to that.
If Osman gathers more strength,
he won't just march to the west.
He'll try to take us first.
The weakness of Seljuks, absence
of any dominant power encourages him.
You'll be the iron fist then, Mustafa.
You raised me for today.
I was raised with your fire,
not with my bey's slowness.
Now I will burn them.
We know Romanos' intentions.
He wants to beat us and be a
hero in Constantinople.
He is a very dangerous man, Osman Bey.
We need to be cautious.
Who is he working with?
What kind of a game he is playing?
We don't know who is he working with yet.
But I know that he is more cunning
than the devil.
If he didn't have an ear
among us...
he wouldn't be so confident.
There is a traitor sending
news to Rome.
And when the road to Bursa opens,
he'll try to face us.
To find it out first, it's better
to be close to Rome.
So, I need you.
Don't derange yourself in Bursa.
You'll keep trading there
like a merchant.
Trade builds friendships.
Don't worry.
Our friendship with the lord
of Bursa will improve.
Road of Bursa you said.
Are we thinking the same thing?
It appears so, Kosses.
We'll take Yenişehir first.
I'll take Yenişehir and
make it my capital.
Then, the conquest of Bursa and many
others will be easier.
All the secret doors in Bursa and
Yenişehir will open to you.
Kosses.
The weakest side of Bursa...
the gate that should be
entered first.
Tell me all of this.
Don't worry, Osman Bey.
You'll learn every detail soon.
Let's move, then.
Yes.
Yes, but...
I have to tell you something
important first.
Why did Cebe come
to these lands?
To die?
To drown Turks in their
own blood!
But you are a disgrace to Genghis Khan!
Erlik Khan damns you!
What does Cebe want?
Cebe asks you!
He wants revenge.
Kazan Khan turned his
back on us.
He prefered his faith over
his people.
Cebe...
will kill everyone behind
Kazan Khan!
Everyone Kazan Khan
showed mercy to...
will meet Cebe's wrath!
Turks, Muslims...
all of them!
What were Osman's brainless followers
doing there, Romanos?
We would only bait them!
I told you to not underestimate Osman!
It was your duty to
seek the right time.
Osman killed many of your men.
I hope you have enough
warriors left.
Only the weak fall, Romanos.
It means that the strongest
warriors are still with me.
Alright.
Then let's come to our deal.
Finding good soldiers...
finding gold...
isn't easy.
Especially if you have a giant
Mongol army behind you.
Tell me about the gold, Romanos.
Slaying the Turks is our job.
Until no Turk and no Muslim
is left in these lands...
I won't sheathe my sword.
I'll kill the damned Turks...
and get gold.
I think it's a good teal.
You'll raze here.
You'll amuse Osman and keep
him behind you.
Until the Byzantine army
comes...
Osman shouldn't be able to
prepare.
So...
do what you know the best.
Burn. Destroy.
Kill.
Give hell to the Turks.
I'm holding the head of the
last Turk who disobeyed me.
He would tell me what to do.
Don't talk high.
So that you can keep talking.
I trust you, Cebe.
You will kill them.
I will kill Osman.
The name of Kayı will be forgotten.
Tomorrow is a big day.
I'll expect news from you.
I take an oath...
I'll drink their blood with the skull
of a different Turkmen everyday.
You are finally speaking what your
heart wanted for years, Kosses.
I wanted to be sure, Sheik Edebali.
I've read a lot.
I've thought a lot.
Lately, my heart wasn't in peace.
The only thing that will give
me peace is Islam.
You already declared your faith
in your hearth, it seems.
Now, you'll say it with your heart.
I bear witness that there is no god
but Allah...
and I bear witness that Muhammad
is the servant and Messenger of Allah.
May it be blessed.
I'm grateful.
I found this path thanks to you.
The path was in you, Kosses.
Allah destined you to it.
Your heart wanted to be on
the right path. It happened.
You will live as a Muslim...
and give your last breath as a believer,
inshallah.
Amin.
With the name of Allah.
Kosses. You were my brother
for life.
Now you are my brother
in faith too.
Thank Allah.
We fought shoulder to shoulder
on the battlefield.
Now we take sides as an ummah.
Thank Allah.
I'm going to Bursa as a Muslim.
If I can't return...
give me your blessing.
It's yours.
May Allah protect you.
Inshallah...
with your helps, we'll take Yenişehir
and Bursa.
But you won't come.
You'll wait for us in Bursa.
Alright.
-Alps.
-My bey.
Here, huh?
My bey, she is here.
Hiding.
You say so...
Where is the most beautiful
girl of this tribe, I wonder!
Where is my girl Akça?
Where is my green-eyed one?
I've been searching for her
since dawn!
She wouldn't go anywhere without
seeing her father, but...
Anyway.
Let's see who'll be the prettiest girl
of the tribe.
If you have another girl...
she'll be the prettiest girl in
this tribe.
Let her be.
Let her be, my daughter.
You will be her older sister.
Come here.
I'm here.
Look at her!
Fatma.
Come.
I'm here.
My little sheep!
You'll have a sibling.
As your older brothers and sisters
took care of you.
So will you.
You are an older sister now.
Alright. I'll take care
of her but...
I grew up...
I'll have a sibling too...
then, like my older brothers
and sisters, I want weapons too!
Look at her!
My girl, just ask for a weapon.
I'll have the most beautiful one
forged for you!
Deal?
I want a horse too.
Fatma.
But you'll have a weapon
forged. You promised!
Yes. I'll have the prettiest
one forged for you.
Come on.
After I learn how to use it,
I'll join the sisters.
Look at you!
Mashallah to her.
Mashallah.
Come.
Let's say I gave the weapon.
What will happen?
I'll go to war.
Look at you!
-Do you hear it, alps? To war!
-Mashallah.
Mashallah, my bey.
My bey.
I found it while I was tracing.
Mongol commander Cebe.
He wants an audience.
Finally we met, Osman.
Bey.
I heard a lot about you in Konya.
I'm here with Sultan Alahaddin's order.
I rode here, chasing the fleeing
Mongol soldiers of Sülemiş Revolt.
My warriors set camp at the valley.
I'm here until I find those
marauders.
What do you want from me?
No one knows here better than you,
Osman Bey.
I want you to help me find them.
As you read it. That's how Sultan
Alahaddin orders.
I'll help.
I'll help, surely.
But Sultan Alahaddin, why is he sending
a Mongol commander for this?
Are there no soldiers left
in Konya?
You wouldn't know why, Osman Bey.
And I don't know why the Turkmens
I saw on the road are coming to you.
Sülemiş revolted for his own benefit.
If Kazan Khan had made him the governor...
there would be no revolt.
Then he fled to the Mamelukes like
a coward!
Wouldn't you be afraid?
Never!
Cebe...
never leaves before finishing
what he started.
I will find those marauders...
and make them pay.
My bey, Ali Bey is coming.
My alps will accompany you.
Then...
let's find those marauders.
-Cerkutay.
-My bey.
Stay close to him.
As my bey orders.
Alps!
Be cautious.
We trust you to get on
the way.
Taking İnegöl isn't enough, it seems.
If you can't control some bandits,
how can you control İnegöl?
You are speaking over your position.
But I'll not hear it because
of your pain.
Now stop the haste.
Whoever done this...
will pay for it!
While you were greeting us with
smooth talk in the caravansarai...
our alps were dying here.
Is this how you protect
the roads?
Shame on you!
Now, think about what you'll
say to Ali Bey.
Don't worry.
We'll find and punish
the responsible.
But now, it's time to chase
those traitors.
Wasting time with words
won't do us good.
Kutan, go to the tribe and
inform Osman Bey.
We'll trace the traitors
who did this.
Then catch up with us.
As you order, my bey.
Recover soon, sisters.
Thank you, my bey.
Welcome, Ali Bey!
Welcome!
Welcome! Welcome, my bey!
Welcome! Welcome!
Welcome! You honored us!
Mashallah!
Come on, now.
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam!
Welcome, Ali Bey.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
What a greeting that was!
Mashallah to your alps.
And they are right up there
with the alps.
True.
It's certain that they'll be valiants
just like their father Osman.
Inshallah.
Inshallah. Come on.
Come on.
Little sister!
You will also be capable.
I can tell!
Your great grandmother, Mother Haime.
She was very capable.
You seem a little shy, huh?
She is shy at first times.
But she is very vocal, Ali Bey.
When he gets comfortalbe,
she gets everyone tired.
May Allah protect your children.
-Amin.
May Allah bless you.
Thank you.
You honored our tribe, Ali Bey.
I'm honored. Thank you.
You took a long way.
You must be tired.
Eat our meal,
drink our ayran.
Let's get in.
-Come.
-Thank you.
It's been a long time since I last
ate Kayı meal.
I missed it!
Thank you!
They separated to get rid
of us.
Konur, go this way with
the alps.
We'll go this way with you.
Be cautious.
Come on.
Thank Allah for this reunion, Ali Bey.
Thank Allah, Osman Bey.
Thank Allah.
While the Mongols are around,
my caravan was in danger but...
Turgut Bey and Konur Alps's
escort...
gave us security.
Thank you.
You are our friend.
Of course, you would do the same for us.
The Mongols fleeing Sülemiş Revolt.
They came here.
They are raiding all the caravans.
And Rome is sharpening its
fangs against us.
The conquest of İnegöl must've
made Constantinople feel sick.
As you ruin the enemy like this...
we feel prouder.
Thank you.
But we aren't doing the conquests
for ourselves.
Firstly, for Allah's approval...
and then, for the prosperity of the
Muslims and all the oppressed.
You carry your ancestors' hearts.
Otherwise...
...the conquest of Inegol
would be impossible.
Thank you.
But Inegol's conquest...
...is not enough for our dreams.
What is that you thinking of, Osman Bey?
Bursa.
Bursa is our target.
Sons.
Tracks end here
But why?
You neither protect our goods...
...nor you are able to track.
You are supposed to be the boss of Inegol
but doesn't seem like that, Turgut Bey.
What is your intention?
Do you want to drive me crazy and
get yourself killed?
My intention is to tell the truths
instead of keeping them in my mind.
You are not as powerful as you seem.
You are not even strong enough to
protect your things.
You are just following a dumb man.
That man you call dumb is my brother
Osman Bey, whose way is my way.
Weigh your words, old man.
Turgut Bey.
You talk too much.
Face me if you can!
You are too young.
Stop it.
Do not get yourself killed here.
It's poisonous.
It can even kill a lion.
Turgut won't die.
He will suffer.
Cebe's plan will work precisely.
Meet my poison, Turgut.
These are not from us, Alps!
Draw your swords!
You are not strong at all, Turgut Bey.
Stop, what are you doing?!
Their mouths are tight!
Mustafa should be safe.
Or our plan will be wasted.
Osman would see the truth.
Ali would see the truth!
I will tell you only one thing.
The thightest mouth
is a dead man's mouth.
You don't need to live.
We are here for avenge.
You are here for gold.
Osman wouldn't believe it...
...if Ahmet was alive.
Well said, Aizek.
You are smart.
You are smarter than Arius.
Thousands of swords are not necessary
in order to win a battle.
Sometimes just a dagger is enough.
Sir, someone is approaching.
Okay.
Let's leave then.
Let them kill each other.
You trace well.
Do they teach how to trace in Kayi?
I learned how to send cruels to hell
in Kayi tribe.
I learned how to trace way before.
When did you learn it?
Has it been a very long time?
Why are you keep asking?
Are you jealous of my skills?
Mongols, huh.
No one can trace like a Mongol.
Neither on land nor at sky.
This way.
Yenisehir is key for Bursa.
This is why I will conquer Yenisehir first.
But Ali Bey, I need your support.
I would be wasting my Bey post if I
didn't participate in such a blessed duty.
I stand with you.
Eyvallah (thank you)
You gathered the bravest Alps
from Caucasus to these lands.
They praised those valiants very much.
I would like to see them.
Can I come in, my Bey?
Here they are.
Come!
Eagles are famous in Caucasus.
Turhan.
He killed those who wanted to kill me.
Samil.
He has been with us for a quite long time.
He hunt them all like an eagle
in Inegol.
Hay Masha Allah valiants.
Tell me how it winds...
...in Caucasus.
When a drop of blood spills here...
The same drop of
blood spills in Caucasus as well.
Both our pain and happiness are shared.
Masha Allah
(praise be)
My valiant.
You came from Susha.
What brought you here?
What brings a Turk is a call for war.
I am here to become a Ghazi,
a martyr if destined.
There are many Beys.
Is it only Osman Bey who is fighting?
Why do you stand with Osman Bey?
There are many Beys.
They are all fighting.
Why are you in Osman Bey's tent?
I came to congratulate his conquests.
We are here to spill our blood,
die in those conquests!
You talk about other Beys.
All are turning their back on each other.
But Osman Bey
always goes forward.
Both east and west are ours.
We will fight until the flag of Islam
raises in the whole world.
May your way be open.
Eyvallah.
(Thank you)
Masha Allah valiants.
(Praise be!)
Can I come in my Bey?
Come, Kutan.
My Bey.
They raided Ali Bey's caravan.
There are many deads and woundeds.
Shahzade Mustafa and Atabey
are after them.
Who?
Who did this, Osman Bey?
Looks like Mongols.
Calm down.
We'll do what we need to do.
How can I calm down, Osman Bey?
Everybody knows how much I rely on Kayis!
Am I wrong?
Oh, Osman Bey.
Do not set your eyes on forward
before you provide the security.
We have enemies everywhere.
You were careless.
My Creator gave us power...
...we ended the cruelty in this land.
Whoever hurts my guests, the goods
of my guests...
...will pay dearly.
Do not worry about this.
I wouldn't.
I couldn't have felt more safe even if
I provided the security for my caravan.
But, the outcome.
I only care the outcome, Osman Bey.
Then be patient to see the end of things,
Ali Bey.
Be patient.
Murderer!
What is happening here, Turgut Bey?
He killed my Atabey!
They raided us Cerkutay.
There is something wrong with this arr!
I will kill you...
...to let everyone know!
I will blow your head!
Stop, Shehzade.
This is not the place to secure the justice!
If you love your life...
...give Turgut to me.
Turgut Bey will go to the tents.
Osman Bey will judge!
Whoever disobeys this rule
disobeys Osman Bey.
Let it be.
But what Turgut deserves is death!
If Turgut gets forgiven,
I will not step back.
Alps!
Care Turgut Bey's wound!
Come on, come on!
Come no brothers!
Come on!
You have too much to worry.
I will keep tracing myself.
I will cut those who did this into slices!
I came to say that
Beys want to see Ali Bey...
...as I can see, there must be
something more important.
We entrusted our goods and lives.
Our trust is destroyed, Barkin Bey.
This is the important issue!
Stop there.
Devils are on their work.
New borders, new enemies.
We surely know that
we'll overcome all.
Inshallah.
(If Allah permits)
My Son!
Mustafa!
Son!
Ahmet.
Cerkutay! Konur!
What happened?
When we arrived...
I'll tell you what happened Osman Bey!
Turgut Bey who you sent
with us to protect us...
...killed Atabey!
They would say
"Kayi tribe is traitors' place"...
...but we didn't expect so quickly!
Turgut Bey?
What the hell?
Cerkutay!
Konur!
Tell me!
Turgut Bey!
How did this happen?
Tell me, son!
We were tracing Mongols who raided us.
That traitor Turgut teased Atabey!
He stabbed him in the chest!
His Alps shoot arrows to me.
No.
Stop there.
Are these true?
Cerkutay!
Konur!
Tell me!
My Bey.
When we arrived...
Turgut Bey...
...was taking this dagger out
of Atabey's chest.
This is what we have seen, my Bey.
He is right, my Bey.
Let Turgut Bey come to himself.
Then we'll judge.
The guilt is obvious.
The guilty is obvious.
What is there to judge, Osman Bey?
You know the tradition, Ali Bey!
You know it better than me!
What I know is that reprisal is a must!
Life for life!
Blood for blood!
Ali Bey!
Ali Bey
Let go of me, Osman Bey!
Ali Bey!
Stop!
This is not a place to judge!
You are not to judge either!
This is Kayi tribe.
Everything goes by the justice here.
That's it!
Well done!
We both got the best of this case.
I got the best of the best.
I earned gold for doing what I love
to do the most, killing Turks!
What more can I desire?
But remember.
There are so much gold to earn.
Don't worry.
Do not let your anger blind you, Ali Bey.
Even the best eyes can missee here.
We supported you, came here.
First, it was about our goods.
We didn't care much.
I thought "not more important
than my son's life!"
But now...
My Mustafa is wounded.
Atabey Ahmet , who I considered
as a brother, is dead!
You protect Turgut Bey's life!
Do you think your men
have more value than mine!
Ali Bey!
It is not the case of whose man's life!
Allah is the one who gives life!
If this is done by Turgut Bey...
I will judge him.
The right justice is the fast justice.
Not the delayed justice!
All the men say they witnessed!
You don't even believe your own
Alps' words.
The one who judges by words...
...gets captivated the other day.
This is Kayi tribe.
This is the home of deceptive cases!
Even the truths may seem like lies!
Now be aware.
If you are not...
...then no one can wake you up
from the sleep of unawareness.
Ali Bey.
I will take Turgut from you, Osman Bey.
Either bring Turgut's head and throw
it at my feet...
...or we'll have a fight in which
the blood of brothers spills.
You always mentioned the
importance of life!
A thousand lives for a life!
Osman Bey!
The decision is yours now.
Ali Bey.
It is now my mission to...
...cut the head of whoever tries
to set you and I against each other...
...and throw his head at your feet.
Alps.
My Bey.
Turgut Bey!
Are you fine?
Osman Bey.
Tell me, tell me.
Tell me, Turgut Bey!
No.
He is not well.
Take him to the healhouse!
When the truth gets revealed...
...this dagger will destoy the chest of
whoever tried to set us against each other!
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com